



# Adam Mischke





+1 - 931 - 998 - 0046

mischke@protonmail.com

# Summary

Dedicated Full-stack Engineer with a strong work ethic, known for quick learning and commitment to teamwork while mentoring junior developers. Brings 5 years of startup experience in agile and TDD environments, taking ownership of both process and solution lifecycles. Previously served 6 years as an Engineer in the United States Navy, specializing in the Ship's Self-Defense System.

### Education

### Middle Tennessee State University

Murfreesboro, Tennessee Bachelor of Science - Computer Science; Minor in Mathematics July 2014 - June 2018 Awards / Memberships: Dean's List 2014-2018, Member of Association of Computing Machinery (ACM), Member of the Upsilon Pi Epsilon Computer Honor Society

### Skills

Python, Swift, JavaScript, Typescript, C++, SQL, Bash, Solidity • Languages:

Django, Flask, NodeJS, React, NextJS, SwiftUI Frameworks:

Docker, Terraform, Pivotal Tracker, GIT, PostgreSQL, Fastlane, Hardhat, Redux Tools:

• Platforms: Mac, Linux, Web, iOS, AWS, GCP, Firebase, Github, Datadog, Sentry, Code Climate, CircleCI, Vercel

• Soft Skills: Leadership, Problem Solving, Strong Communication, Time Management

### Experience

# Ford - Experience Design

Remote February 2023 - Current

Expert Creative Technologist (Full-time)

- Software Expert: Demonstrated technical expertise and adaptability by developing multiple prototypes for the BlueCruise Audio Tour Guide Experience iOS app and the Apple Vision Pro BlueCruise experience, showcasing proficiency in cutting-edge technologies like React, React Native, iOS, CarPlay, VisionOS, Android, and Android Auto.
- Leadership: Demonstrated leadership and a collaborative approach by actively contributing to the XD Process and Deliverables team, focusing on enhancing operational efficiency, minimizing waste, and developing tools like the Agile Sprint Canvas Board for improved communication and transparency across stakeholders.

# Open3 - Qualified Digital Art Platform

Remote

Senior Full-stack Engineer (Full-time)

July 2022 - December 2022

- o Focused Execution: Built in 3 months from the ground up, a website experience that had over 17,000 verified users and hosted 68 partners and their projects that included brands such as Liquid Death.
- Leadership: Worked alongside Artists and Brands to generate digital art and deployed over 33 smart contracts that sold over 100,000 art pieces.

### FunFunFun Inc. - Gen Z Dating

Full-stack Engineer (Full-time)

May 2020 - June 2022

- o First Engineering Hire: Subject Matter Expert on a live updating video dating app that integrated with TikTok with over 10,000 users, where users could like, match, and message each-other.
- Backend: Built a Django and GraphQL REST API and a matching algorithm to pair users together with alike parameters. Created a series of Firebase, Firestore, and Google Storage Typescript triggers to create a video processing pipeline that asynchronously cut over 8,000 videos.
- Frontend: Deployed a complete SwiftUI iOS app from the ground up to app store. Contributed to an internal Typescript React webpage to police uploaded media and content used by admins.
- o DevOps: Used GitHub actions to create an CI/CD pipeline for testing and deploying the backend and iOS using fastlane for multiple environments.

#### Coinmine - Crypto Mining Made Easy

Software Engineer (Full-time - Part-time)

May 2018 - Current

- o First Engineering Hire: Built a plug-and-play cryptocurrency miner that mined 6 different cryptocurrencies 24/7, that a user could control with their iOS or Android phone.
- mineOS: Built and maintained mineOS, an Arch Linux-Based Operating System, onto a small form factor computer. Fabricated the build and deployment tools for distributing mineOS images through a test and build pipeline to remotely update over 5,000 miners.
- o Backend: Used Agile, Extreme Programming and Test Driven Development methodologies to deploy, update, and configure a Django based REST API with over 10,000 users. Created programmatic reports to calculate all accounting owed and owned.
- o DevOps: Arranged and operated analytical, deployment, and pipeline tools such as: CircleCI, Code Climate, Datadog, and Sentry.
- o Communication: Worked with overseas distribution centers in China to construct and create Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) for assembly and manufacturing.

### Caterpillar Financial Services Corporation

Information Services - Network Team (Intern)

May 2017 - July 2017

- Leadership: Led research, meetings, and recommended the replacement of a network team application. Worked as liaison between team members and company solutions, then sought out quote to be implemented into the yearly budget.
- **Problem Solving**: Researched and developed a web dashboard that displayed global network information with Python and Flask using a SQL database. Used JavaScript, J-Query, Bootstrap, AJAX, and Google Charts to form a coherent and simple-to-use website. Implemented a search function that integrated with database calls to speed up information flow.
- o Process Improvement: Six Sigma Green Belt Trained
- Public Speaking: Completed both projects within scope and presented both projects to the entire CAT Financial leadership and received Excellent feedback.

# **United States Navy**

Fire controlman (FC2) - Computer and Network Technician (Full-time)

July 2008 - July 2014

- Leadership: Efficiently led as work center supervisor, supervising 8 personnel in accomplishing over 1,634 maintenance actions with a 94% maintenance accomplishment rate, managing 372 maintenance checks and repairs.
- Security Clearance: Held a Secret Clearance and handled the Electronic Key Management System, which managed 106 classified software programs and hardware systems.
- Preventative & Corrective Maintenance: Upkeep and corrective maintenance of the Ship's Self Defense System, Open
  architecture network server and computer systems, Battle Force Tactical Trainer network, and Cooperative Engagement
  Capability LAN.
- Teamwork: Assisted in the successful overhaul of 3 major system installs with lead engineers to include: Hardware, software, and network installation, troubleshooting to the perfection of the system.